Guide to the Barbara Karkabi Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Research, id135663
  - Health, id135700
    - Mental Health and Terrorism, 2001; id136059 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder, 2001; id136060 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Progressive Supranuclear Palsy, 2002-2003; id136061 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Suicide, 2001; id136062 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Various, 1996, 2001-2008; id136063 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Locations, id135701
    - Beirut, 1997, 2005-2009; id136065 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Darfur, 2006-2007; id136066 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Downtown Houston, undated; id136067 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Iraq, 2005-2007; id136068 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Kokernot Field, undated; id136069 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Lebanon, 2007; id136070 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Lebanon, 2006, 2008; id136071 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Nicaragua, 2007; id136072 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Palestine, 1987; id136073 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Palestine, 2007; id136074 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - SABA (Isper)/Syria, 2007; id136075 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Organizations, id135702
    - Aga Khan Trust for Culture, 2007-2008; id136077 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Association for Women Journalists, 1998-1999; id136078 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Boniuk Center, 2006-2008; id136079 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Brigid’s Place, 2007; id136080 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Center for the American Woman and Politics, 1988; id136081 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Christ Clinic, undated; id136082 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Churches, 2007; id136083 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Community Clinic, 2001; id136084 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Doctor’s Orchestra, 2001; id136085 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Folder not used, id136086 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - European Society of Culture, 2007-2008; id136087 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Foundation for Contemporary Theology, 2007; id136088 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - GLAAD, 2007; id136089 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Holocaust Museum Houston, 2006-2007; id136090 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Houston Area Women’s Center, 1998; id136091 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Houston Hindu Temples, undated; id136092 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Interfaith Ministries, 2007; id136093 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Journalism and Women Symposium, 1989-1994; id136094 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Kahlil Gibran Centennial Foundation, 1991; id136095 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Kohl’s Cares For Kids, 2009; id136096 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - The Monarch School, undated; id136097 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, 2008; id136098 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - National Alliance, 2001; id136099 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - National Organization of Women (NOW), 1985; id136100 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - PFLAG, 2001-2002; id136101 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Rothko Chapel, 2005-2007, 2009; id136102 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Rutherford BH Yates Museum, 2001; id136103 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Saint Francis Sanctuary, 2007; id136104 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - St. Paul Antiochian Orthodox Christian Church, 2007; id136105 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Sisters of Charity of the Incarnate Word, 2008; id136106 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Texas Interfaith Power & Light, 2006; id136107 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Texas Trailblazer, undated; id136108 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - The United States Institute of Peace, undated; id136109 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - University of Houston Friends of Women’s Studies, 2000-2005; id136110 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Vishwa Hindu Parishad of America Houston Chapter, undated; id136111 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - The Women’s Home, 2001; id136112 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Women’s Motivational ministries, April 25, 2009; id136113 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Woodlands Hindu Temple, 2007; id136114 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - People, id135703
    - Addresses, undated; id136116 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Daniel Andrade (Beyonder), 1988; id136117 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Bahai Women, undated; id136118 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Benazir Bhutto, 2007; id136119 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Business Cards, undated; id136120 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Deaths, 2007; id136121 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Archbishop Daniel DiNardo, undated; id136122 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Folder not used, id136123 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Rabbi Irving Greenberg, 2007; id136124 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Jennifer Harbury, 1994-1995; id136125 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Lisa Hernandez, 2002; id136126 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Ashraf Khan, 2001; id136127 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Koshy-Narasiman, 2009; id136128 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Thomas H. Kreneck, undated; id136129 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Murthy-Cugley Wedding, 2002; id136130 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Linse Meadows, 2001; id136131 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Bonnie Eloise Rush Milam, 2002; id136132 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Celia Morris, 1990; id136133 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Sheikha Mozah, 2007; id136134 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Rev. Cedric Pisegna, C.P., undated; id136135 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Chaplain Captain Timothy S. Rosenthal, 2007; id136136 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Saudi Ambassador to the United States Prince Turki Al-Faisal, 2006; id136137 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Maureen Seebar, 1998, 2000; id136138 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Dr. Matthew Sleeth, 2009; id136139 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Various, 1988, 2005, 2007-2009; id136140 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Swami Vidyadhishananda, 2007; id136141 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Jim Wallis, 2008; id136142 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - David Ashley White, 2008; id136143 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Race Issues, id135704
    - Arab-Americans, 1983-1987, 2005; id136145 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Hate Crimes, 2001; id136146 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Houston Immigration, 2008; id136147 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Ross Family, 2001; id136148 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Various, 1997-1998, 2001; id136149 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Religion, id135705
    - Articles, 2005-2007; id136151 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Baha’i, 2006; id136152 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Books, 2008; id136153 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Catholicism, 2005-2008; id136154 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - English Church Brochures, 2008; id136155 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Episcopalians, 2006-2008; id136156 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Focolore, 2007-2008; id136157 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Hare Krishna, 2007-2008; id136158 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hindu, 2004, 2007-2008; id136159 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Interfaith Ministries, 2007-2008; id136160 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Islam and Finance, 2008; id136161 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Judaism, 2008; id136162 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Meditation, 2006; id136163 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Latin Muslims, 2006; id136164 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Latter Day Saints, 2007; id136165 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Methodist, 2007; id136166 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Mormons, 2007; id136167 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Muslims, 2003-2007; id136168 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Muslims, 2006-2009; id136169 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Muslim-Christian Relations, 2008; id136170 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Muslim Immigration, undated; id136171 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Politics and Religion, 2007-2008; id136172 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Polygamy, 2006-2008; id136173 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Religion and Homosexuality, 2008; id136174 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Schools and Religion, 2007; id136175 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Union of Black Episcopalians, 2007; id136176 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Various, 2005-2009; id136177 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Various, 2006; id136178 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Various, id135706
    - Challenger Shuttle, 1986; id136181 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - College, 2005; id136182 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Pets, 2002, 2007; id136183 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Poems, 1993, 2002; id136184 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Story Ideas, 2006-2007; id136185 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - U.S. Religious Landscape Survey, June 2008; id136186 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Various, 2000-2009; id136187 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Weather, 2002; id136188 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Writing Tips, undated; id136190 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Women and Children, id135707
    - Battered Women, 2005; id136192 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Children and Tragedy, 2001; id136193 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Domestic and Child Abuse, 2004; id136194 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Female Children, 1990-1994; id136195 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Lesbian and Gay, 1978-1986; id136196 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Middle East Women, 2007; id136197 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sex Trafficking, 2000-2001, 2008; id136198 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Teens, 2000, 2004; id136199 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Texas Women, 1986; id136200 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Various, 1998-2002; id136201 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - World War II Women, 1995; id136202 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Ephemera, id135664
  This series consists of materials Karkabi collected in the course of her work. Of particular interest are odd religious centered artifacts such as the “Deseret honey” crafted by the Latter Day Saints as well as an unopened tin of adhesive bandages sporting images of Jesus. Also included are two journalism awards won by Karkabi.
  - Calendar, 2002; id136204 (Ovsbox 11, Item 1)
  - Crocheted Shawl, undated; id136205 (Ovsbox 11, Item 2)
  - Deseret Honey, undated; id136206 (Ovsbox 11, Item 3)
  - Face Mask, undated; id136207 (Ovsbox 11, Item 4)
  - Ferrara Coffee Mug, undated; id136208 (Ovsbox 11, Item 5)
  - Francis C. Moore, M.D. Award for Journalism, 1987; id136209 (Ovsbox 11, Item 6)
  - Glass Vase, undated; id136210 (Ovsbox 11, Item 7)
  - Handmade Hat, undated; id136211 (Ovsbox 11, Item 8)
  - Harold Schachern Award, 2008; id136212 (Ovsbox 11, Item 9)
  - Humane Society hat, undated; id136213 (Ovsbox 11, Item 10)
  - Jesus Adhesive Bandages, undated; id136214 (Ovsbox 11, Item 11)
  - Loteria de los Muertos, undated; id136215 (Ovsbox 11, Item 12)
  - “Reflections: If Minnie Fisher Were Here Today,” by Jane Mulholland, undated; id136216 (Ovsbox 11, Item 13)